<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Prism</title>
    <link href="https://prism.ninja/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://prism.ninja" />
    <updated>2022-05-31T17:10:16-07:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>kamonanban</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://prism.ninja</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Pixel 6a: Big Trade Offs</title>
        <author>
            <name>kamonanban</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://prism.ninja/pixel-6a-big-trade-offs/"/>
        <id>https://prism.ninja/pixel-6a-big-trade-offs/</id>

        <updated>2022-05-31T17:09:30-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Google just announced their new A-Series Pixel, and it's taking the concept behind the iPhone SE to the extreme. The Pixel 6a will be rocking the full Google Tensor chip, without the major hardware flaws of the SE, and for nearly the same price! So&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Google just announced their new A-Series Pixel, and it's taking the concept behind the iPhone SE to the extreme. The Pixel 6a will be rocking the full Google Tensor chip, without the major hardware flaws of the SE, and for nearly the same price! So what's the catch? Well, the problem with the Pixel 6a isn't actually the phone itself, it's its big brother, the Pixel 6. The Pixel 6 only costs $600, so are there few enough compromises to justify spending that $150 less?</span></p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://prism.ninja/media/posts/12/google-pixel-6a-fingerprint-sensor-anim.gif" alt="" width="480" height="270"></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Right off the bat, the 6a has a better fingerprint scanner (according to the leaks from Google themselves).</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">(Source: </span><a href="https://www.androidpolice.com/google-pixel-6a-unboxing-video-shows-fingerprint-scanner-not-slow/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Android Police</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">)</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This by itself may be a deal maker to some buyers. Unfortunately, not everything about the 6a can be praised. The screen is only 60hz while manufacturers like Samsung and OnePlus are giving their midrange competitors 120hz panels. The camera is also a disappointment, as unlike the previous A-Series, it doesn't keep the flagship setup, instead opting for the same cameras as the Pixel 5a. These downgrades are fair, seeing how Tensor exists, but again, $150. A feature people have always loved in the A-Series is the headphone jack, which the Pixel 6a omits. Another omission from last year's Pixel 5a is the charger in the box.</span></p>
<p> </p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">All in all, the Pixel 6a is a solid midrange phone. The battery, like all of the A-Series, is supposed to be better than their flagship siblings (🙄), and it has a tried and true camera that has always managed to impress. Compared to the iPhone SE, it actually looks modern (like, come on Apple, the iPhone 8 is dead), so that's a plus. The 6a also will have an IP 67 rating (water resistant; up to one meter in water for 30 minutes) for the extra peace of mind. If you're looking for phones in that price range, the 6a is probably your best bet. It's not the best, but its software makes up for a lot of the downsides. If you can spring the extra $150, you probably won't regret splurging for its bigger sibling.</span></p>
<p> </p>
<p><a href="https://store.google.com/us/magazine/compare_pixel?hl=en-US&amp;toggler1=Pixel+6&amp;toggler2=Pixel+6+Pro&amp;toggler0=Pixel+6a"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Compare the 6 and 6a</span></a></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>How Samsung Fumbled Android 12 (and why it will happen again)</title>
        <author>
            <name>kamonanban</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://prism.ninja/how-samsung-fumbled-android-12-and-why-it-will-happen-again/"/>
        <id>https://prism.ninja/how-samsung-fumbled-android-12-and-why-it-will-happen-again/</id>
            <category term="Prism Exclusives"/>
            <category term="Phones &amp; Tablets"/>

        <updated>2022-05-18T18:10:42-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://prism.ninja/media/posts/9/librewolf_FABPPTc2Ji.png" alt="" />
                    Samsung has been a long lasting android device manufacturer, however, they are infamous for their slow updates and patchy support; Recently, Samsung has been fixing up their act with updates, releasing them faster, and giving more support to devices. However, the Android Twelve update could&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://prism.ninja/media/posts/9/librewolf_FABPPTc2Ji.png" alt="" />
                <p>Samsung has been a long lasting android device manufacturer, however, they are infamous for their slow updates and patchy support; Recently, Samsung has been fixing up their act with updates, releasing them faster, and giving more support to devices. However, the Android Twelve update could have gone much better.<br>(Disclaimer: I am using a Galaxy S10e, my views are reflective of my experiences with these updates, and the flagship devices.)</p>
<p>This story is the first ever Prism Exclusive! Please discuss in the comments.</p>
<p><br>Android 12 Beta:<br>“On September 14, 2021, the One UI 4.0 Android 12 beta went live for the Galaxy S21 series in select markets. It was gradually rolled out in all supported markets. Samsung eventually opened up the beta to the Galaxy Z Fold 3, Galaxy Z Flip 3 and the Galaxy Note 20 series.” (Quote: <a href="https://www.sammobile.com/samsung/android-12-update/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">SamMobile</a>)<br>Initially, problems seemed to arise, Icon theming didn’t extend to google apps, and the Monet palettes generated were excessively vibrant compared to their google counterparts. These problems have not yet been resolved.<br><br>Good Lock:<br>Samsung’s semi-official tweaking hub “Good Lock”, received a multitude of updates for Android 12, most notably, the ability to import custom icon packs. However, this update poses potential legal issues, as refunded icon packs stay in the Good Lock app, available for use. On the good side of Good Lock, icon packs are finally available on the stock “One UI” launcher(albeit with the Good Lock app needed to be downloaded from the Galaxy Store), volume can be adjusted on an app-by-app basis, side-swipe gestures can perform a vast multitude of actions, the recents menu can be completely redesigned; and the keyboard’s colors, animations, and sounds can all be customized. All in all, the Good Lock app really completes the One UI experience.</p>
<p>The Rollout:<br>The rollout of Android 12 and One UI 4.0 was a little shaky, but there were no major setbacks, and some devices got their update months ahead of schedule. The problem arises in the contents of the update. Kevin27 on the Samsung forum said “so I've just checked most of mine are using blue inside, which is the main color of my chosen pallette, I've found 2 using purple instead (which is one of the other 2 colors in my pallette) the Play Store is one, Google Clock app is the other - I don't know why these 2 are using purple instead of the blue.” This update left many people confused, so let’s explain what’s happening in the case of Kevin27. The One ui 4.0 theme selector shows 3 colors per Monet theme.</p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://prism.ninja/media/posts/9/librewolf_VxpaZDHf1Z-2.png" sizes="100vw" srcset="https://prism.ninja/media/posts/9/responsive/librewolf_VxpaZDHf1Z-2-xs.png 300w ,https://prism.ninja/media/posts/9/responsive/librewolf_VxpaZDHf1Z-2-sm.png 480w ,https://prism.ninja/media/posts/9/responsive/librewolf_VxpaZDHf1Z-2-md.png 768w ,https://prism.ninja/media/posts/9/responsive/librewolf_VxpaZDHf1Z-2-lg.png 1024w ,https://prism.ninja/media/posts/9/responsive/librewolf_VxpaZDHf1Z-2-xl.png 1360w ,https://prism.ninja/media/posts/9/responsive/librewolf_VxpaZDHf1Z-2-2xl.png 1600w"  alt="" width="292" height="80"></figure>
<p>The palettes being shown with this little amount of description leads to people not knowing what their own pallettes even mean. The main color of Kevin’s pallette was actually supposed to be purple, but with Samsung’s poor implementation of Monet, the apps that should be themed purple were left the default android 11 blue. As to my personal experiences, a Samsung support agent had the same problems as me, and could not provide a fix on this. What happened? To be honest, I really have no clue how Samsung’s implementation didn’t affect all of the android apps, however, I have heard from developers that there are multiple ways to implement monet into apps(and that they are all very convoluted), and it looks like whatever implementation the indie devs used worked a lot better than the Google implementation. </p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://prism.ninja/media/posts/9/Screenshot_20220209-211149_Firefox.jpg" sizes="100vw" srcset="https://prism.ninja/media/posts/9/responsive/Screenshot_20220209-211149_Firefox-xs.jpg 300w ,https://prism.ninja/media/posts/9/responsive/Screenshot_20220209-211149_Firefox-sm.jpg 480w ,https://prism.ninja/media/posts/9/responsive/Screenshot_20220209-211149_Firefox-md.jpg 768w ,https://prism.ninja/media/posts/9/responsive/Screenshot_20220209-211149_Firefox-lg.jpg 1024w ,https://prism.ninja/media/posts/9/responsive/Screenshot_20220209-211149_Firefox-xl.jpg 1360w ,https://prism.ninja/media/posts/9/responsive/Screenshot_20220209-211149_Firefox-2xl.jpg 1600w"  alt="A samsung support member reproducing the issue" width="1080" height="2280"></figure>
<p><br><br>The solution: <br>With One UI 4.1, Samsung seemingly fixed all these issues. The real question is what was wrong? All apps that support Monet theming do work(for me, at the time of writing); but the timeline it took to get there is very bumpy. On January 15th, I received the One UI 4.0 update, and it was not until March that my phone was supposed to get 4.1. To clarify, One UI 4.1 was part of the March security patch, and it started a slow release to the s10 lineup in (reportedly) March 28th. However, that was a Switzerland only release. On April 26th, it started a US release, on Unlocked phones only(which is odd, because usually carriers release their updates faster). On April 29th, nearly two months after "March", the rest of the s10 lineup was updated to One UI 4.1. The Galaxy A21 is still in the release phase of this update, nearly two and a half months later.</p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://prism.ninja/media/posts/9/Screenshot_20220429-174512_System-updates.jpg" sizes="100vw" srcset="https://prism.ninja/media/posts/9/responsive/Screenshot_20220429-174512_System-updates-xs.jpg 300w ,https://prism.ninja/media/posts/9/responsive/Screenshot_20220429-174512_System-updates-sm.jpg 480w ,https://prism.ninja/media/posts/9/responsive/Screenshot_20220429-174512_System-updates-md.jpg 768w ,https://prism.ninja/media/posts/9/responsive/Screenshot_20220429-174512_System-updates-lg.jpg 1024w ,https://prism.ninja/media/posts/9/responsive/Screenshot_20220429-174512_System-updates-xl.jpg 1360w ,https://prism.ninja/media/posts/9/responsive/Screenshot_20220429-174512_System-updates-2xl.jpg 1600w"  alt="" width="1080" height="2280"></figure>
<p><br><br>The solution to the solution:<br>    Quite simply, Samsung has too many phones; from the A series to the Z series and S and M and W. And there are multiple phones in these lineups a year, and those phones have different models, and those different models use different carriers, and those different carriers can be in different regions that Samsung controls the updates for. The iPhone(no matter your or my opinion) is stable. With only one series a year (with the occasional SE), Apple can devote much more resources to developing good software for each device, and support them longer. If Samsung adopts a better phone tiering model, they might be able to prevent this from happening again.<br><br>Thinking about the future, Android 13 is supposed to add themed icons to all icons, (given that a developer provides a line art icon to their play store listing or apk) but Samsung’s themed icon aesthetic is not the same as Google’s; these clashing ideas may lead to a very poorly implemented design language in the future. Samsung claims to be supporting their new phones for even longer times, but until they clean up their act, this is bound to happen again.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>About Us</title>
        <author>
            <name>kamonanban</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://prism.ninja/about-us/"/>
        <id>https://prism.ninja/about-us/</id>
            <category term="Prism"/>

        <updated>2022-05-31T16:54:09-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    - Head Author | Kamonanban "Hi, I'm kamonanban, I started this blog/news platform in early 2022 after I closed my YouTube channel (as of now). I am a big believer on an open-source future, and am trying to advocate for free and collaborative news. Im&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p class="align-center">- Head Author | Kamonanban </p>
<p>"Hi, I'm kamonanban, I started this blog/news platform in early 2022 after I closed my YouTube channel (as of now). I am a big believer on an open-source future, and am trying to advocate for free and collaborative news. Im Armenian 🇦🇲, I love hiking, running and being in the outdoors. Sustainability is important for me, and I will keep making strides to help this website, and other projects be clean for the environment. also I really like ducks."</p>
<p class="align-center">- Co-Author | Imaperson.exe</p>
<p>"Hi, I'm a person. I like to code, mainly in JavaScript and other languages with similar syntax. If you've never met me, I am a person. That is all you need to know. Check out some of my fun code projects that are usually either unoriginal or pointless."</p>
<h6 class="align-center">More:</h6>
<p>Maybe this next page can be about YOU! Join our Discord to submit your stories to Prism. <a href="https://discord.gg/nyMCH2n4dV" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Prism Discord Server [clickable]</a></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Changelog</title>
        <author>
            <name>kamonanban</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://prism.ninja/changelog/"/>
        <id>https://prism.ninja/changelog/</id>
            <category term="Prism"/>

        <updated>2022-05-31T17:10:16-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Prism v1.2.1 - reworked about us - added placeholder matrix links and sustainability message to footer - increased hero size TODO: add matrix room(synced to discord) Prism v1.2 -analytics are through cloudflare, and shouldn't track you across sites -added new prism.ninja domain. huge thanks to&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>Prism v1.2.1</p>
<p>- reworked about us</p>
<p>- added placeholder matrix links and sustainability message to footer</p>
<p>- increased hero size</p>
<p>TODO: add matrix room(synced to discord)</p>
<p>Prism v1.2</p>
<p>-analytics are through cloudflare, and shouldn't track you across sites</p>
<p>-added new prism.ninja domain. huge thanks to <a href="https://mecanik.dev">mecanik.dev</a> for buying it this time around</p>
<p>-renamed github, some pages may be BROKEN</p>
<p>-Prism Exclusives tag</p>
<p>-tab colors on supported browsers</p>
<p>Prism v1.1.2</p>
<p>-remapped entire web layout from github pages to cloudflare</p>
<p>-added sitemap to google crawler</p>
<p>-added site to google search (hopefully)</p>
<p>TODO: add wearable posts, rework about us, add non-google analytics</p>
<p>Prism v1.1.1</p>
<p>-started google indexing</p>
<p>-verified site for google custom search</p>
<p>-added github &amp; discord to footer</p>
<p>TODO: add wearables posts, fix analytics</p>
<p>Prism v1.1</p>
<p>-fixed comments</p>
<p>-re-enabled search(will not work until indexing finishes)</p>
<p>Prism v1.0</p>
<p>-Public release</p>
<p>-fixed links in footer</p>
<p>-added "about us"</p>
<p>-temporarily disabled search functionality</p>
<p>TODO: add wearables tab, fix search, add page analytics </p>
<p>Prism v0.9.1</p>
<p>- finalised hero tab</p>
<p>TODO: add wearables tab,</p>
<p>Prism v0.9.0</p>
<p>- added changelog</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Grand Opening!</title>
        <author>
            <name>kamonanban</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://prism.ninja/grand-opening/"/>
        <id>https://prism.ninja/grand-opening/</id>

        <updated>2022-05-10T07:05:09-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Today, the prism blog launches! Our current goals are to add more stories from all across the tech space! -kamonanban feel free to discuss in the comments (currently they require me to approve them)
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>Today, the prism blog launches! Our current goals are to add more stories from all across the tech space! <span style="color: var(--text-primary-color); font-family: var(--editor-font-family); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);">-kamonanban</span></p>
<p>feel free to discuss in the comments (currently they require me to approve them)  </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Write For Us!</title>
        <author>
            <name>kamonanban</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://prism.ninja/write-for-us/"/>
        <id>https://prism.ninja/write-for-us/</id>
            <category term="Prism"/>

        <updated>2022-05-20T17:19:56-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Prism is founded on the premise of collaboration, there are two ways to submit a story for free. (please note, prism makes ZERO money, and will not compensate you for your work, I am not compensated either, think of it like an open forum!) How&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>Prism is founded on the premise of collaboration, there are two ways to submit a story for free.</p>
<p>(please note, prism makes ZERO money, and will not compensate you for your work, I am not compensated either, think of it like an open forum!)</p>
<p>How to write for Prism:</p>
<p>join the kamonanban discord: <a href="https://discord.gg/nyMCH2n4dV">https://discord.gg/nyMCH2n4dV</a></p>
<div class="post__iframe"><iframe loading="lazy" width="350" height="500" src="https://canary.discord.com/widget?id=971953930525360138&amp;theme=dark" allowtransparency="true" frameborder="0" sandbox="allow-popups allow-popups-to-escape-sandbox allow-same-origin allow-scripts"></iframe></div>
<p>email me @ 1ubpxi8il [at symbol] mozmail.com</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>nothing special: Nothing OS Launcher (beta)</title>
        <author>
            <name>kamonanban</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://prism.ninja/nothing-special-nothing-os-launcher-beta/"/>
        <id>https://prism.ninja/nothing-special-nothing-os-launcher-beta/</id>
            <category term="Phones &amp; Tablets"/>
            <category term="Concepts"/>

        <updated>2022-05-10T22:42:02-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://prism.ninja/media/posts/3/rp749arw.bmp" alt="" />
                    Former OnePlus CEO Carl Pei’s “Nothing” just released a beta of the launcher for upcoming “Nothing phone(1)”, but only officially for the Samsung s21, 22, pixel 5, 6 and supposedly Oneplus phones in the near future. Update: The launcher is now officially available on all&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://prism.ninja/media/posts/3/rp749arw.bmp" alt="" />
                <p>Former OnePlus CEO Carl Pei’s “Nothing” just released a beta of the launcher for upcoming “Nothing phone(1)”, but only officially for the Samsung s21, 22, pixel 5, 6 and supposedly Oneplus phones in the near future.</p>
<p>Update: The launcher is now officially available on all android 11+ phones on the <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.nothing.launcher">Play Store [clickable]</a></p>
<blockquote id="ips_uid_3886_2" class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
<div class="ipsQuote_citation ipsQuote_open"><span style="font-family: var(--font-serif); color: var(--text-primary-color); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);">“As an early preview, the Nothing Launcher includes a number of tweaks and tuning including what Pei’s firm refers to as “Max Icons” and “Max Folders.” This allows you to press and hold app icons or folders and increase the space taken on your home screen. The level of customization is not quite up to the levels of Nova Launcher with a simple AOSP or Pixel Launcher-like approach taken here.” -Damien Wilde@9to5Google</span></div>
</blockquote>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>My thoughts:</strong></p>
<p> This is a very odd way for a company to release a software product; and although I appreciate the sentiment of being in ties with the community, this is not on par with community &amp; enthusiast style customization. The only major distinct feature of this vs the pixel launcher would be the native icon pack support, 3 widgets, and a custom font in menus.</p>
<p>Using some <em>unorthodox</em> methods, I got it working on my s10e, and was immediately taken aback by the permanent google search bar, that does not look to be removable. It also lacks material you support, the stock widget menu looks very out of place, and the aesthetic of Nothing only works well with a black and white wallpaper and icon pack.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Gallery:</p>
<div class="gallery-wrapper"><div class="gallery"  data-is-empty="false" data-translation="Add images" data-columns="3">
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://prism.ninja/media/posts/3/gallery/872979D3-C576-4591-B1A2-FA2A65EC5427.thumb.jpeg.2dc74e0766bca0c4a4dcb9c7c81e5a75.jpeg" data-size="1000x750"><img loading="lazy" src="https://prism.ninja/media/posts/3/gallery/872979D3-C576-4591-B1A2-FA2A65EC5427.thumb.jpeg.2dc74e0766bca0c4a4dcb9c7c81e5a75-thumbnail.jpeg" alt="" width="720" height="540"></a>
<figcaption>The google search bar looks out of place on the black and white default background.</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://prism.ninja/media/posts/3/gallery/C062BD14-28B3-4C49-A4A6-33B017871E21.thumb.jpeg.4dcf326809e2e5e640b015a579ac6db1.jpeg" data-size="1000x750"><img loading="lazy" src="https://prism.ninja/media/posts/3/gallery/C062BD14-28B3-4C49-A4A6-33B017871E21.thumb.jpeg.4dcf326809e2e5e640b015a579ac6db1-thumbnail.jpeg" alt="" width="720" height="540"></a>
<figcaption>When that nothing effect looks good, it REALLY looks good</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://prism.ninja/media/posts/3/gallery/image.thumb.jpeg.0854a8ca572c11c0dc35b0420d114abc.jpeg" data-size="710x1500"><img loading="lazy" src="https://prism.ninja/media/posts/3/gallery/image.thumb.jpeg.0854a8ca572c11c0dc35b0420d114abc-thumbnail.jpeg" alt="" width="710" height="1500"></a>
<figcaption>Material you is kinda broken.</figcaption>
</figure>
</div></div>
<p><strong>Sources</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://9to5google.com/2022/04/28/nothing-launcher-launches-in-beta-for-galaxy-s21-s22-pixel-5-and-6-series/" rel="external nofollow noopener" target="_blank">https://9to5google.com/2022/04/28/nothing-launcher-launches-in-beta-for-galaxy-s21-s22-pixel-5-and-6-series/</a></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Google&#x27;s Little Signals</title>
        <author>
            <name>kamonanban</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://prism.ninja/googles-little-signals/"/>
        <id>https://prism.ninja/googles-little-signals/</id>
            <category term="Concepts"/>

        <updated>2022-05-10T22:42:08-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://prism.ninja/media/posts/2/librewolf_sak7XbzYq4.png" alt="" />
                    Little Signals, a DIY ambient computing kit by Google. Recently, Google unveiled a project called “little signals”, it is their biggest exploration into ambient computing since google assistant. Essentially, little signals are notification alerts that are designed to be as little of an intrusion into&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://prism.ninja/media/posts/2/librewolf_sak7XbzYq4.png" alt="" />
                <div class="ipsType_normal ipsType_richText ipsPadding_bottom ipsContained" data-role="commentContent" data-controller="core.front.core.lightboxedImages">
<p>Little Signals, a DIY ambient computing kit by Google.</p>
<p>Recently, Google unveiled a project called “little signals”, it is their biggest exploration into ambient computing since google assistant. Essentially, little signals are notification alerts that are designed to be as little of an intrusion into life as possible.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>this is not on track to become an actual Made by Google product. (Source: 9to5Google),</p>
</blockquote>
<p>But there are instructions to make your own DIY little signal, with the nest aesthetic with an arruino at the website: <a href="https://littlesignals.withgoogle.com/" rel="external nofollow noopener" target="_blank">https://littlesignals.withgoogle.com/</a></p>
<p>What counts as an alert:</p>
<div id="ips_uid_4232_2" class="ipsSpoiler" data-ipsspoiler="">
<div class="ipsSpoiler_contents ipsClearfix">
<ul>
<li>What seems to be a notification seems to be completely different from the types of notifications you might get on your phone, the example given in the documentation and supplied code are based on the environment, with possible triggers such as weather, rainfall, temperature, and other quantifiable alerts.</li>
<li>Example (using the air little signal): the arduino pings the openweathermap.org api, and it says that it has begun raining, the air little signal sends a gust of air into the plant on top of it. You notice the plant move, and are prompted to open blinds, a phone, or more, to get more information. The end goal of this is to eliminate the need for a phone as a feed, and get all the alerts you need without thinking about it. </li>
<li>Example 2 (using the movement little signal) (DISCLAIMER: this is purely my idea, and there are no official guides on making this trigger):</li>
</ul>
<p>the arduino gets the forecast for the day (not putting an api because there is none listed officially), and the pegs move to see how the temp is throughout the day. These values would be arbitrary, but combined with another trigger to see the current temperature, you can see it all at a glance, without the tech being overtly visible.</p>
</div>
</div>
<p>Meet the objects:</p>
<div id="ips_uid_4232_3" class="ipsSpoiler" data-ipsspoiler="">
<div class="ipsSpoiler_contents ipsClearfix">Disclaimer: these are google’s unofficial mockups, the ones provided by their schematics are made with card stock. You might get varying degrees of success with a 3D printed chassis. <br><a href="https://youtu.be/XdSwhyFegF8" rel="external nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Video by google</a></div>
<blockquote>
<div class="ipsSpoiler_contents ipsClearfix"><figure class="shrinkToFit"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://9to5google.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2022/04/Google-Little-Signals-air.png" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="https://9to5google.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2022/04/Google-Little-Signals-air.png" width="1536" height="693"></figure> <br><strong>Air</strong> interacts with its close surroundings. Pulses of air move nearby items, like the leaves of a plant, to attract attention.<figure class="shrinkToFit"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://9to5google.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2022/04/Google-Little-Signals-button.png" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="https://9to5google.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2022/04/Google-Little-Signals-button.png" width="1536" height="693"></figure><br><strong>Button</strong> combines scale and sound to communicate and provide control. The top twists – right for more details, left for less – and grows as it receives information. It plays a tone when full.<figure class="shrinkToFit"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://9to5google.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2022/04/Google-Little-Signals-movement.png" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="https://9to5google.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2022/04/Google-Little-Signals-movement.png" width="1536" height="693"></figure><br><strong>Movement</strong> features seven pegs that graphically represent information – like a calendar or timer– through their height and motion. The pegs work individually or as a group, and are tapped for simple input.<figure class="shrinkToFit"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://9to5google.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2022/04/Google-Little-Signals-rhythm.png" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="https://9to5google.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2022/04/Google-Little-Signals-rhythm.png" width="1536" height="693"></figure><br><strong>Rhythm</strong> generates ambient sounds. Qualities of the melody convey qualities of the information, like its importance, urgency, or tone. A wave over the object, or simply turning it over, mutes it.<figure class="shrinkToFit"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://9to5google.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2022/04/Google-Little-Signals-shadow.png" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="https://9to5google.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2022/04/Google-Little-Signals-shadow.png" width="1536" height="693"></figure><br><strong>Shadow</strong> communicates through the movements of the shadow it casts. They show the object’s status, like gently breathing when active or stretching in response to presence.<figure class="shrinkToFit"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://9to5google.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2022/04/Google-Little-Signals-tap.png" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="https://9to5google.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2022/04/Google-Little-Signals-tap.png" width="1536" height="693"></figure><br><strong>Tap</strong> makes use of surfaces to create sounds that act as notifications. A stronger tap means more pressing news.</div>
</blockquote>
</div>
<p>How to build your own Little Signals:</p>
<p>You can build your own Little Signals by following the guide downloadable <a href="https://littlesignals.withgoogle.com/download/Experiment%20With%20Little%20Signals.zip" rel="external nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Here</a>, this guide requires an arduino, and has most of the objects made out of card stock, however, you can probably 3D print your own chassis for them(dont forget ventilation).</p>
<p>Impact of this project:</p>
<p>Google is showing increased interest in ambient computing, and with this being their first real project into it, it shows a glimpse into the future of the google ecosystem. My personal prediction is the eventual death of the phone as anything more than a content (games, videos, and art) creation and consuming facilitator, and work related facilities. But using the phone as a means of asking questions, checking your surroundings, and other things the google assistant can already do, will eventually fizzle away from the phone and be replaced by cues in your environment.</p>
<p>Sources: <a href="https://9to5google.com/2022/04/14/google-little-signals-experiment/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">9to5Google</a> for transcriptions of the google website &amp; quotes</p>
</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
